<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Somay Jain</title>
    <description>A senior-year computer science undergrad from IIIT-H. Have a keen interest in high performance computing and it&#39;s blend with computer graphics and vision. Having worked on HFOSS projects for the past 2 years, enthusiastic about open source software development.</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC : Week 1 Experiences</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first week has almost come to an end. I must say, this was a pretty productive week. To start off, I set up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://demo.ssf.sahanafoundation.org/&quot;&gt;demo instance&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ssf.sahanafoundation.org/&quot;&gt;Sunflower&lt;/a&gt; on which I would push the newer code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The targets of the week were to - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redesign the website to use a bootstrap based theme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fetch updates from Github, Twitter, Sahana wiki, Tasks list and Sahana Tickets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redesigning the webpage was fun, as we know it, bootstrap is quite awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before redesigning - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://yourdomain.com/imgs/sahana-before.png&quot; alt=&quot;sahana-before&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After redesigning - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://yourdomain.com/imgs/sahana-after.png&quot; alt=&quot;sahana-after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I am not that good at web design, but I guess I did a decent enough job :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for fetching the updates, I decided to use the RSS and Atom feeds for Github and Twitter. The Sahana wiki is hosted on trac, so the RSS feeds for the wiki updates and tickets were also easily available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tasks lists, which were stored in Sunflower’s database itself, it was a bit tricky to generate the RSS feed. It involved exporting the data in a xml format. But, there was XSLT to the rescue! Putting in some effort with XSLT, I was able to generate a RSS feed for the tasks list as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having all the feeds, I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/feed&quot;&gt;Google Feed API&lt;/a&gt; to parse the feeds and display them in a tabbed manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, I would say, I struggled a bit with the documentation of Google Feed API, it could have been better, but nonetheless, I am really glad with the overall progress of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having read this post, if you have a bit more patience, do check out the demo site &lt;a href=&quot;http://demo.ssf.sahanafoundation.org&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– SJ&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 23:52:36 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/gsoc/2014/05/25/week1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/gsoc/2014/05/25/week1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Summer of Code with Sahana Software Foundation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been selected for Google Summer of Code (again!). I will be working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://sahanafoundation.org&quot;&gt;Sahana Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; on their humanitarian FOSS project &lt;a href=&quot;http://eden.sahanafoundation.org&quot;&gt;Sahana Eden&lt;/a&gt;. It has been almost two years since I am working with Sahana, and every single day has proved to be a promising learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of GSoC, I will be working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://ssf.sahanafoundation.org&quot;&gt;Sahana Sunflower&lt;/a&gt;, which will be used as a community managment tool to see what everyone is interested in working on and for people to report problems or seek assistance regarding Sahana Eden. It will have information about the deployments, members and volunteers of Sahana Eden around the globe. Also, giving stats about the community work, it will be useful in getting funds for this HFOSS! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a critical tool for Sahana, it gives a warm satisfying feel to take up the responsibility of building it during the summer. This is one of the best things about the program, you get to work on projects that are really important and do make an impact on a wider audience. Also, you learn to write good quality code, rather than some code which ‘just-works’ somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Source is an addiction, and I hope that it stays with me for a long long time :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I am also working on computational fluid dynamics, trying to simulate fluid flows on GPUs in parallel using CUDA. With over a million particle interacting with each other, according to some crazy physics equations, it is challenging but fun to watch the fluids flow on your computer screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look around, there is a lot to keep yourself occupied with, atleast I have, so looking forward to a great summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– SJ&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 23:52:36 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/gsoc/2014/05/01/gsoc-sahana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/gsoc/2014/05/01/gsoc-sahana/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
